Inventory of the Samuel Myers Papers 1808-1812
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Special Collections, Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Samuel Myers Papers 1808-1812
Special Collections Research Center
00/05/UA 5.098
0.06
This collection is composed of the correspondence, a certificate, Myers' commencement remarks, and a list of books of College of William and Mary student Samuel Myers. The letters includes Myers' career plans, events in Williamsburg including a near-duel Myers was involved in, and other matters.
Myers, Samuel, 1790-1829; Smith, Augustine arrangement
Administrative Information
Conditions Governing Access
Collection is open to all researchers.
Custodial History
This collection was formerly part of the University Archives Faculty-Alumni File Collection (UA 10).
Biographical Note
Samuel Myers (1790-1829) lawyer in Norfolk, Pensacola, Florida, and son of Moses Myers. Further information about this individual or organization may be available in the Special Collections Research Center Wiki: http://scrc.swem.wm.edu/wiki/index.php/Samuel Myers.
Scope and Contents
This collection is composed of the correspondence, a certificate, Myers' commencement remarks, and a list of books of College of William and Mary student Samuel Myers. The letters includes Myers' career plans, events in Williamsburg including a near-duel Myers was involved in, and other matters.
Additional Information
Related Materials
Samuel Myers Papers(Mss. 95 M99); Myers Family Papers (Mss. 98 M99 Myers II); see the SCRC Collections Database for other collections related to members of the Myers family: http://scrc.swem.wm.edu/
Index Terms
This Collection is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Genre/Form of Material:
Correspondence
Topical Term:
College of William and Mary--Faculty and Staff; College of William and Mary--History--19th century.; College of William and Mary--Students.; Dueling--Virginia.
Detailed Description of the Collection
- Correspondence, 1808-1812; id63576 (Folder 1)
  - Letter to John Myers, April 10-17, 1808; id63608 (Folder 1)
  - Certificate of Approbation from James Madison to Samuel Myers, July 15, 1808; id63609 (Folder 1)
  - Letter from Littleton Tazewell, August 10, 1808; id63614 (Folder 1)
  - Letter to His Family, October 26, 1808; id63577 (Folder 1)
  - Letter from Mosers Myers, January 30, 1809; id63615 (Folder 1)
  - Letters addressed to John Myer, February 2 and 7, 1809; id63616 (Folder 1)
  - Speech, July 4, 1809; id63617 (Folder 1)
  - Letter from Augustine C. Smith to Samuel Myers, July 11, 1809; id63618 (Folder 1)
  - Letter from Augustine C. Smith to Samuel Myers, August 16, 1809; id63644 (Folder 1)
  - Letter from Augustine C. Smith to Samuel Myers, November 6, 1809; id63645 (Folder 1)
  - Letter from Augustine C. Smith to Samuel Myers, February 11, 1810; id63620 (Folder 1)
  - Letter from William C. Rives to Samuel Myers, March 29, 1810; id63621 (Folder 1)
  - List of books either used or requested by Myers, undated; id63622 (Folder 1)